# John Sauter

Location: Nashua, New Hampshire, USA e-mail: <u>John Sauter@systemeyescomputerstore.com</u>

Telephone: (603) 424-1188

Linkedin: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/john-sauter-9580b2232/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/john-sauter-9580b2232/</a>
Portfolio: <a href="https://johnsauter.github.io/UNH\_Bootcamp-20-React\_Portfolio/">https://johnsauter.github.io/UNH\_Bootcamp-20-React\_Portfolio/</a>

GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/JohnSauter">https://github.com/JohnSauter</a>

# Summary

Experienced computer programmer who understands the discipline necessary to build products that work, on time and within budget. Experience working in many roles in academia and industry, including team leader, product development, implementation, quality assurance and customer support. As a Principal Software Engineer, developed products for Digital Equipment Corporation, a world-class computer manufacturer. Obtained a certificate in full-stack coding from the University of New Hampshire, developing skills in JavaScript and its add-on modules for front-end and back-end Web development.

# **Projects**

- Find Dry Chargers | Link to GitHub | Link to Deployed Project
  - Overview: Lets long-distance drivers of electric vehicles find chargers that are within range, in the right direction, and not being rained on.
  - Responsibilities: Originated the idea, guided the design, did much of the back-end coding including integration of other participant's work, wrote the presentation slides.
  - o Tools Used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Foundation for Sites and the Crypto package
- Plant Selection Planner | <u>Link to GitHub</u> | <u>Link to Deployed Project</u>
  - Overview: Saves time for gardeners and nursery managers when selecting plants for a garden.
  - Responsibilities: Collaborated on the design, wrote the login front end and parts of the back end, wrote the presentation slides, demonstrated the application during the presentation.
  - Tools Used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Foundation for Sites, Node.js, Express.js, Handlebars.js, MySQL, GitHub, Heroku, JawsDB, Sequelize, and nodemailer.
- Matchmaker | <u>Link to GitHub</u> | <u>Link to Deployed Project</u>
  - Overview: bringing like-minded people together
  - Responsibilities: Developed the idea, led the design, wrote the login front end and most of the back end, demonstrated the application during the presentation
  - Tools Used: HTML, CSS, JavasScript, React, Node.js, Mongoose, MongoDB, GraphQL, Heroku, Heroku Atlas, JWT, express, doteny, Stripe, and Nodemailer

#### **Technical Skills**

- Front end: HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, Foundation for Sites, JavaScript, JQuery, React.
- Back-end: Python, C, Bash, Node.js, Express.js, MySQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, MongoOse, MongoDB Atlas, GraphQL, Heroku.

# **Work Experience**

#### Assistant Administrator for UPS in Londonderry, NH

April 2019 to February 2022

- Oversaw the hour-to-hour operation of the building, making sure parts flowed smoothly through the system, and handling special requests from customers.
- Developed documentation for the routine processes to maintain consistency in operational procedures and efficiency in training new assistant administrators.

### IT Technician for UPS in Londonderry, NH and Chelmsford, MA June 2015 to April 2019

- Installed, maintained and diagnosed technical problems with computers, printers, and other equipment, thus ensuring day-to-day efficiency of operations could be maintained.
- Fixed problems in other locations remotely or by traveling there since not all buildings have resident technical support.
- Maintained an adequate supply of spares so that if a piece of equipment failed the defective item could be replaced quickly.

# IT Technician for Kforce and Mōdis in New Hampshire, Massachusetts, May 2009 to June 2015 Maine and New York

- Replaced servers in Home Depot stores, keeping their servers up-to-date and consistent from store-to-store.
- Installed Hewlett-Packard printers in U.S. Postal Service facilities, Bank of America branch offices and Liberty Mutual offices, ensuring that each location has fast and reliable printing.
- Upgraded Liberty Mutual computers running Microsoft Windows XP so their computers would continue to receive security updates.
- Surveyed, installed, upgraded and removed computers at Liberty Mutual offices, Genesis Healthcare and Lahey Clinic so they could benefit from the speed and reliability of modern computers.
- Developed and piloted a process for converting all of Corning's personal computers to Microsoft Windows 7 so their computers would continue to receive security updates.
- Upgraded or replaced 3,000 computers at the Dartmouth-Hitchcock Medical Center in Lebanon, NH, working with a team, so
  that Dartmouth-Hitchcock would not be running an obsolete version of Microsoft Windows that would no longer receive
  security updates.
- Supported for declining to install a printer without help that required a four-man lift so that the installation could be completed safely the following week when Kforce assigned two technicians to the task.

#### **Education**

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development from the University of New Hampshire, September, 2022. This is a 24-week intensive program focused on technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, SQL, MongoDB, Heroku, Node.js and its many modules.